

Dr Arpita Mazumdar

E-mail: arpitamazumdar.hit@gmail.com

Profile URL:

https://vidwan.inflibnet.ac.in//profile/332557

Orcid Id: 0000-0002-1644-6782 Phone: 8945525596, 9433964998

Address: Purba Medinipur ,West Bengal,India - 721657

Expertise

Computer Science Interdisciplinary SCI

Arpita Mazumdar is a self driven, diligent, and energetic person. She is employed with Haldia Institute of Technology as an assistant professor in the department of computer science and engineering. She has pursued her Ph. D degree under the University of Engineering and Management Kolkata after earning her MTech degree in Computer Science and Engineering from Haldia Institute of Technology. She has 17 years of academic experience in teaching.

Work experience

1. Haldia Institute of Technology 2014 — Present

Assistant Professor (Grade-II) Purba Medinipur

2. St. Marys Technical Campus Kolkata 286 2011 — 2013

Assistant Professor (Grade-I) 24 Paraganas North

Education

1. Ph D - 2023

University of Engineering & Management Kolkata

2. M. Tech - 2011

Haldia Institute of Technology

3. MCA - 2009

IGNOU Regional Centre Raghunathgani, West Bengal

Honours and Awards

1. Invited Talk on "ISAA: Mobile Application and Intervention" in Continuing Rehabilitation Education Program (CRE) - 2024

Organized by Rehabilitation Council of India (A statutory body of Ministry of Social Justice and Empowerment)

 Jury award paper presentation competition on Women's Empoermenr & Women's Right in This Century - 2023

Wajood Foundation

3. Invited talk on the topic "ICT-based intervention for ASD" in Workshop on "Applications of Information Technology for Autism" -2022

organized by the Centre for Development of Advanced Computing (CDAC), Kolkata

4. Research interview- " mHealth Study Developer interview" - 2021

Department of Paediatrics, Oregon Health & Science University, USA

5. WIPRO CERTIFIED FACULTY on J2EE - 2018

WIPRO LTD

Membership In Professional Bodies

- Computer Society of India Kolkata Chapter, 2024 Member
- 2. **IGNOU**, 2014 Academic Counsellor

Membership In Committees

1. Board of Studies, 2020 Member

2. Examination Committee, 2018
Member

3. Alumni Committee, 2014 Member

Patent

 MULTI- MODEL LANGUAGE ACQUISITION APPARATUS FOR NON- NATIVE ENGLISH USERS

Inventor(s): Dr.T.SRI DEVI, Dr. V. SAMUEL MORRIS , Mr. R. KATHIRAVAN ,Dr. PREETI CHITKARA ,Dr. SALOMAN RAJU YARLAGADDA ,Dr.V.DEEPHA ,Dr. ARPITA MAZUMDAR ,Dr. LILA SIMON ,Dr. K. SHAHEEN , Dr. BIKASH BEPARI , Dr. CHANCHAL KUMAR DE ,Mr.J LOGESHWARAN, Assignee:

Published: 2023-12-29

2. A COMPREHENSIVE APPROACH FOR MANAGING AUTISM IN INDIAN SOCIETY

Inventor(s): Dr. Arpita Mazumdar, Dr. Mallika Banerjee, Dr. Biswajoy Chatterjee, Dr. Susmit Maity,

Assignee:

Published: 2024-02-23

Publication

1. CRACK CAMPUS PLACEMENTS

Dr. Susmit Maity, Dr. Arpita Mazumdar CRACK CAMPUS PLACEMENTS, Volume First, Year 2024, Pages 75

2. Machine learning based autism screening tool—a modified approach.

Mazumdar, A., Chatterjee, B., Banerjee, M. et al. Multimedia Tools and Applications, Volume , Year 2024, Pages 1-18

3. An integrated autism management platform for readiness of inclusive

schooling

Arpita Mazumdar, Mallika Banerjee, Biswajoy Chatterjee Futuristic Trends in Social Sciences, Volume 3, Year 2024, Pages 18-25

Assistive Technology for Pedagogical Support and Application of Data Analysis in Neurodevelopmental Disability

Arpita Mazumdar ., Biswajoy Chatterjee ., Mallika Banerjee ., Irfan H. Bhati ., Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems, Volume 490, Year 2023, Pages 11-18

5. Assistive Technology for Pedagogical Support and Application of Data Analysis in Neurodevelopmental Disability

Arpita Mazumdar, Mallika Banerjee, Biswajoy Chatterjee, Irfan Bhati LNNS, vol 490. Springer, Singapore., Volume 490, Year 2022, Pages

6. Mobile application based early educational intervention for children with autism-a pilot trial

Arpita Mazumdar ., Mallika Banerjee ., Biswajoy Chatterjee ., Sayan Saha ., Gauri Shankar Gupta ., Disability and Rehabilitation: Assistive Technology, Volume , Year 2021

7. MACHINE LEARNING MODEL FOR PREDICTION OF SMARTPHONE ADDICTION

Arpita Mazumdar

Turkish Journal of Computer and Mathematics Education (TURCOMAT), Volume, Year 2020, Pages

8. An Integrated Autism Management Platform

Arpita Mazumdar, Biswajoy Chatterjee International Conference on Autism 2020: Autism Diversity and Integration, Volume , Year 2020, Pages

Mobile application based modified screening and assessment tools for children with autism

Arpita Mazumdar ., Biswajoy Chatterjee ., Mallika Banerjee ., Irfan H Bhati ., International Journal of Interactive Mobile Technologies, Volume 13, Year 2019, Pages 159-166

A Secure Image Steganography using Efficient Map based LSB Technique (SISEMLT)

Jana, Manasi; Mazumdar, Arpita; Datta, Kankana International Journal of Computer Science and software engineering, Volume , Year 2016, Pages

11. An Effective Dynamic Quantum Round Robin (EDQRR) CPU Scheduling Algorithm

Datta, Kankana; Jana, Manasi; Mazumdar, Arpita International Journal of Computer Applications, Volume, Year 2015, Pages

12. A Secure Off-line Electronic Payment System Based on Bilinear Pairings and Signcryption

Debasis Giri, Arpita Mazumdar International Journal of Soft Computing and Engineering , Volume , Year 2013, Pages

13. On-line electronic payment system using signcryption

Arpita Mazumdar ., Debasis Giri ., Procedia Technology, Volume , Year 2012, Pages

> Downloaded from <u>Vidwan</u>: Expert Database & National Researcher's Network <u>https://vidwan.inflibnet.ac.in/</u>